smarterselect.com 2019-06-11

# Privacy Policy - SmarterSelect

## **Our Commitment to Privacy**

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.

## **The Information We Collect:**

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the SmarterSelect website. On some pages, you submit personal information to subscribe to the SmarterSelect service. The types of personal information collected at these pages may include:

Name  
Address  
E-mail address  
Phone number  
(etc.)

On some pages, you submit personal information to apply for program (e.g. scholarships, grants, awards, etc). In this circumstance, the types of personal information collected may include:

Name  
Address  
E-mail address  
Phone number  
Social security number  
Education information  
(etc.)

The Way We Use Information:

We use the information you provide about yourself when placing an order only to complete that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order (e.g. credit card companies, clearinghouses and banks).

We use the information you provide about yourself when applying for a program only to complete that application. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that application (e.g. scholarship, grant, or award providers).

We do not control how these third parties use such information, but we do ask them to disclose via their own Privacy Policies how they use personal information provided to them.

We use return e-mail addresses to answer the e-mail we receive and to provide updates regarding the service. Such addresses are not shared with outside parties.

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

## **Mandatory Communications**

SmarterSelect sends all newly registered users a welcome e-mail to verify their e-mail addresses. Users may receive e-mails as a function of providing the SmarterSelect service. At times, SmarterSelect sends service announcements to its users. Users cannot unsubscribe from service delivery e-mails and from service announcements that discuss changes that affect their SmarterSelect accounts.

## **Optional Communications**

Users may receive occasional e-newsletters containing information on SmarterSelect products, services and announcements. SmarterSelect provides you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving such optional communications by indicating your desire to opt-out. If you would like to opt out of receiving communications from us please notify us.

## **Disclosures of Personal Information**

In general, it is not SmarterSelect’s practice to disclose personal information to third parties. We may share personal information in two instances.

Firstly, SmarterSelect may share personal information with our contractors and service providers in order to maintain, enhance, or add to the functionality of the website. Secondly, we may share personal information with third parties such as the government or other entities when required to by law or as required by court order.

## **Non-Personal Information That We Collect**

When you use the website, our servers (which may be hosted by a third party service provider) may collect information indirectly and automatically (through, for example, the use of your “IP address”) about your activities while visiting the website, including the web pages you view and the times you view them and information about the browser you are using. We do not link browsing information to the personal information you submit to us; we use this browsing information for internal purposes such as to help understand how the website is being used and to improve it, and for systems administration purposes. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. In some cases your IP address stays the same from browser session to browser session; but if you use a consumer Internet access provider, your IP address probably varies from session to session.

## **Our Commitment to Data Security**

SmarterSelect has implemented reasonable measures to protect against unauthorized access to and unlawful interception or processing of personal information that SmarterSelect stores and controls. However, no website can fully eliminate security risks. Third parties may circumvent our security measures to unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications.

## **Our Commitment to Children’s Privacy:**

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13 without their parent’s permission, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13.

## **How You Can Correct Your Information**

You can correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information by sending us a request that credibly shows error to info@smarterselect.com.

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

## **How to Contact Us**

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please send us an e-mail at info@smarterselect.com.

## **Effective Date**

September 14, 2007
